### DAYO AWOBEKU

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Egbeda, Lagos, 100276, Nigeria

#### ABOUT ME

An ambitious problem-solving web developer with experience building user-friendly applications, with pixelperfect design implementations using the React.js framework and Next.js framework. I ensure the writing of well-optimized and scalable code, achieving a time to interactive (TTI) of approximately 1.2seconds and application performance scores of over 80%.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

University of Ibadan, Ibadan

Bachelor of Science in the Department of Biomedical Laboratory Science.

#### LINKS

### Portfolio:

http://dayoawobeku.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/day <u>oawobeku</u>

Twitter:

https://www.twitter.com/dayoaw

<u>obeku</u>

GitHub:

https://www.github.com/dayoaw <u>obeku</u>

#### SKILLS

React Js

**Javascript** 

Tailwind CSS

Next Js

Bootstrap Figma

Adobe XD

Strong design skills

Strong analytical skills

GraphQl

### WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Dojah | Lagos | Aug 2021 - Present

Worked in conjunction with a team that is building the Fastest KYC and User Onboarding Platform in Africa to help users and companies manage user identity across Africa.

Stack: JavaScript, React JS, Next JS, Redux, React-Query, TailwindCSS

- Created scalable reusable components for react client.
- Created optimized reusable custom hooks.
- Integrated API endpoints on the client application, admin dashboard, and front-facing landing page.
- Worked on technical refinement documents for user stories.
- Collaborated with team members using the SCRUM framework.
- Created close to pixel-perfect user interfaces on the client application, admin dashboard, front-facing landing page, and widgets.
- Applied good SEO principles and ensured that the user application and landing page follow them.

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Outlierz | Lagos | Jan 2021 - Jul 2021 **Contract**

Worked on the frontend architecture of a startup in Lagos, Nigeria, dedicated to the discovery and exposure of talented athletes emerging from Africa.

Stack: React, HTML5, CSS3

- Collaborated with web designers to talk about the layout and design of the
- Built the entire website from beginning to end.
- Ensured cross-platform compatibility.

#### PRODUCT DESIGNER | Decasoft | Lagos | Feb 2021 - Apr 2021 **Contract**

Worked with another product designer to redesign the entire admin application for Decasoft, a company highly skilled in the business of creating internet-based applications, mobile apps, and system integration.

Stack: Figma, Notion

- Carried out extensive user research, and created wireframes and prototypes for the application.
- Created high-fidelity mockups for the application.
- Collaborated with developers and the company's representative to ensure the finished product aligned with the company's goals.

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Wedding Planer | Lagos | Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

Worked on the frontend architecture of a wedding planner landing page in Lagos, Nigeria, a website for intending couples to plan their ceremony with the help of a professional.

Stack: React, HTML5, CSS3

- Collaborated with web designers to talk about the layout and design of the project.
- Built the entire website from beginning to end.
- Ensured cross-platform compatibility.

# **PROJECTS**

## **DO DEEL** | Lagos

A Mobile Application for digital onboarding CDS (Community Development Service) in Nigeria that automates the total user experience from registration to completion during his/her service year as a digital onboader.

- Link: https://www.dodeelcds.com.ng
- Position: Product designer, Frontend Developer
- Technology Used: React, Redux, Firebase, Figma
- Features: Registration system, attendance system, real-time chat system, business onboarding

### INTERNSHIP

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Zuri Team | Lagos | Feb 2021 - Jun 2021 Worked with a team of about 20 individuals to build an Escrow platform that serves as a third party between buyers and sellers for B2C companies.

Stack: React JS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Figma

- Designed usable and visually-appealing user interfaces with Figma.
- Built the user interfaces to be as close to pixel-perfection and responsive on all screen sizes.
- Created scalable reusable components for future use.
- Integrated API endpoints on the user dashboard.
- Optimized components for optimum performance.